## **ERIC SAI KIT CHEUNG**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

## **PROFILE**

I've owned and operated a food business in Hawaii & Brooklyn, selfpublished a fiction novel, and am now a Full-stack Developer specializing in React & Redux, JavaScript, and Ruby & Rails.

I love to build aesthetically pleasing projects, find creative solutions to problems, and am an avid food adventurer & cat instagram follower.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **FLATIRON SCHOOL**

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT FEBRUARY 2020 – JUNE 2020

React & Redux, JavaScript, Ruby & Rails, SQL and PostgreSQL

### SOKA UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA BACHELOR OF ARTS AUGUST 2008 – MAY 2012

Social Behavioral Sciences - 3.8 GPA

## CONTACT



Eric.Saikit.Cheung@gmail.com



646.637.1808



https://ericskcheung.com



www.linkedin.com/in/eric-sk-cheung



erock\_esquire

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### HIES INC • FRONT-END DEVELOPER • JULY 2020 – AUGUST 2020

Designed & rebuilt HIES company website using React JS & Redux, & SASS/SCSS.

- **Redesigned** & built entire HIES company website to be modern, manageable, and business & user-friendly. Utilized React Router for URL address routing.
- **Incorporated** PIXI.js to create realistic moving water effect on hero image. Recreated original hero image using Adobe Photoshop for higher resolution.
- **Organized** over 20 company services into 4 manageable categories, composed descriptions for each service, and added search feature for services.

#### **CURBALERT • FULL STACK DEVELOPER • JUNE 2020**

React JS & Redux, Ruby on Rails with PostgreSQL web app allowing users to post images & details of unwanted items on street onto a public map.

- Engineered codebase synchronizing Geolocation & Google Geocode API to translate latitude/longitude coordinates into addresses. Incorporated Google Directions API by decoding address polylines and response keys to be plotted on Leaflet API map, allowing users to see directions and distance to items.
- **Collaborated** functionality between AWS S3 Cloud & Rails Active Storage to store user post images on cloud bucket through Rails back-end API.

#### **HANGOUTS • FULL STACK DEVELOPER • MAY 2020**

React JS and Ruby on Rails with PostgreSQL web app allowing users to plan meetups at location calculated to be equal distance between all participants.

- **Architected** a Rails back-end call to YELP Search API to provide restaurant suggestions at user current coordinates and requested coordinates, then plotted with detailed markers on Leaflet API map.
- **Composed** function to calculate a midpoint location between a group of users from coordinate data retrieved by Geolocation & Google Geocode API. Coordinates plotted to Leaflet map, simultaneously passing parameters to YELP Search API.

# **BANZAI PHRESH •** OWNER/SOLE PROPRIETOR • APRIL 2016 – JUNE 2018

Owned & operated restaurants at two locations. Oversaw restaurant design, customer service, cooking, financials, and logistical operation of the business.

- Ala Moana Mall Honolulu, Hl. We averaged 100 customers a day, maintained a 30% profit margin, with 4.5 star reviews on Yelp.
- Smorgasburg Market Brooklyn, NY. We averaged 200 customers a day and maintained a 25% profit margin.
- Managed logistical problems such as strict time management, division of labor, inventory tracking & ordering deadlines, and maintaining quality of service & food.

#### KINGS OF FORTUNE • AUTHOR/WRITER • 2014

Self-published an action/adventure fiction novel.

• Received 5 of 5 stars on San Francisco Book Review, 4 of 5 stars on Portland Book Review, and featured review on Kirkus magazine.